<problem display_name="Force Diagram - String and Spring">
<script type="loncapa/python">
<![CDATA[
import vectordraw
grader = vectordraw.Grader()
]]>
</script>
<p>
The figure below shows a box that weighs 6.0 Newtons resting motionless on a table while a spring scale pulls to the right with a force of 3.0 N, and a string pulls to the left with a force of 2.0 N. If we let FG represent the weight of the object, FS represent the force of the spring, and FT represent the force exerted by the string, draw a force diagram using the appropriately labeled vectors.
</p>
<p>
  <i>This is a vector drawing problem type. Use your mouse, or the "add vector" button, to place and drag vectors to the blue points. Be sure to place the correctly labeled vector at the appropriate location. </i>
</p>
<customresponse cfn="grader.cfn">
  <jsinput gradefn="getInput"
    get_statefn="getState"
    set_statefn="setState"
    initial_state='{}'
    width="800"
    height="500"
    html_file="/static/10_FDiagrams_LC1_Q1.html"
    />
</customresponse>
  <solution>
<div class="detailed-solution">
<p>Explanation</p>
  <img src="/static/IMG_4.1.2_1_1.jpg" width="400" height="300"/>
<p>In addition to considering the forces explicitly described, this question requires you to consider the fact that the object is not accelerating. We know that the sum of forces must be zero in both the horizontal and vertical directions. The gravitational force exerted on the object, \(F_G\), is downward, and must be opposed by an upward force of equal magnitude and opposite direction exerted by the table on the object. This normal force is labeled \(F_N\). 
  </p><p>It’s a little trickier to determine that there is also a missing horizontal vector, since there are two horizontal forces in the opposite directions given. However, \(F_T\) to the left is less in magnitude than \(F_S\) to the right. This means that there must be an additional force acting on the box with a magnitude of 1N pointed toward the left (in this case, friction, labeled \(F_f\)). Note that you do not need to know anything specific about the normal force or friction to answer this question. All you need to realize is that if the object is not accelerating, the free body diagram must be drawn in such a way as to indicate a net force of zero in both the horizontal and vertical directions. Only one free body diagram satisfies this condition.</p>

</div>
</solution>
</problem>
